ROBERTO FLÓREZ ABLAN

M.Sc Physics student

rflorezablan@gmail.comRoberto Flórez

49 176 58705367

nttps://github.com/rupof/

I am a M.Sc Physics student at the University of Stuttgart, member of the International Max Planck Research School (IMPRS) for Condensed Matter Science. I am currently working at the intersection between Quantum Computing (Numerical/Theory) and Machine Learning (Kernel Methods).

EDUCATION

M.Sc in Physics (current) Grade: 1.1

University of Stuttgart and

Max Planck Research School for Condensed Matter Science

♥ Stuttgart, Germany

Microcertificate in Artificial Intelligence

University of Stuttgart Artificial Intelligence Software Academy (AISA)

m 06/2023 - EXP 06/2024

♀ Stuttgart, Germany

B.Sc in Physics

Grade: 82.2%, final class rank: 2nd best out of 26 students.

Federal University of São Carlos (UFSCar)

1 02/2018 - 04/2022

♀ São Carlos, SP, Brazil

EXPERIENCE

Master's Thesis Research and Student Research Assistant

Fraunhofer IPA - Quantum Computing group

08/2023 - current

♀ Stuttgart, Germany

Numeric simulations of Quantum Machine Learning Algorithms. Research on Quantum Kernel Methods and Applications to differential equations.

Research advisor: Dr. Jan Schnabel, group of Dr. Marco Roth.

Academic research project in Large Language Models Institute For Theoretical Physics III

1 09/2023 - 02/2024

♥ Stuttgart, Germany

 Deep Learning research project: Implemented a Transformer Network (LLM) to learn the probability distributions from the Schrödinger's equation for a free gaussian particle. (See poster)

Research advisor: Prof. Dr. Mathias Scheurer.

Undergraduate research project, scholarship by FAPESP UFSCar - Light-atom group

10/2022 10/2022

♥ São Carlos, SP, Brazil

• High performance computing numeric simulations (Python - QuTiP) of quantum optics and atomic physics. Research on dipole-dipole contributions to biphoton emissions of four-wave-mixing (FWM) processes.

Research advisor: Prof. Dr. Romain Bachelard.

Undergraduate research project, scholarship by CNPQ UFSCar - Opto-electronics and magneto-optics group (GOMA)

10/2021 10/2021

São Carlos, SP, Brazil

 van der Waals Heteroestructures: experimental setup of an optical characterization experiment for two-dimensional materials and some optical characterizations. Research advisor: Prof. Dr. Yara Galvão Gobato.



RELEVANT COURSES

Master level:

- Quantum Computing I and II
- Atomic Physics I and II
- Advanced Quantum Mechanics
- Condensed Matter Theory
- Machine Learning

Bachelor level:

- Quantum Mechanics 1 and 2
- Introduction to Quantum Computing
- Statistical Mechanics
- Computational Physics 1 and 2

AWARDS

- Scholarship recipient (2023-2024) of the Deutschlandstipendium. Merit scholarship "for international top-class talent".
- Scholarship recipient (2022-2024) of the International Max Planck Research School (IMPRS) for Condensed Matter Science Fellowship program for highly qualified master students.
- Poster presented at the EOSBF 2022, the largest topical meeting of the Brazilian Physical Society. Titled: Collective effects in biphoton generation of a FWM process.
- **Presentation done** at UFSCar Scientific Initiation Congress 2022. Titled: *Optical properties of two-dimensional semiconductor materials.*
- Merit Scholarship 2020/1 and 2020/2scholarship granted to foreign students of academic excellence who are part of the cultural agreement PEC-G.
- Selected by cultural agreement PEC-G (2018) to pursue undergraduate studies in Brazil.

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) Portuguese (Fluent) English (Fluent) German (B1)

